Victor Vernilli

victor.vernilli@gmail.com

Lisbon, Portugal

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/vernilli

Portfolio: https://vernilli.com/

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I'm a Product Designer who believes that we can make people's life easier, even in the most complex areas. For me, when people hate an experience it's because there are some gaps to be filled focusing on users. This became even truer when I was working with mobile ads and I had to make ads more functional, to help in people's daily routine.

KEY SKILLS

Technical Skills

- User-centered design process
- Qualitative and quantitative methods
- Usability testing
- Data analysis
- Prototyping
- Adobe Creative Suite
- Figma, Adobe XD, Sketch, InVision, Zeplin and Marvel App.
- Wordpress, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript vanilla, JQuery, Vue and React JS

Personal Skills

- Team player
- Doer
- I get along well with all kinds of coworkers, from technical people to sales people
- When I love something, I focus all my energy on it.

EXPERIENCES

PRODUCT DESIGNER

Indie Campers
www.indiecampers.com
Lisbon - Portugal
Nov 2019 - Today

Indie Campers offers campervan hiring across Europe and provide local travel advice, highlighting special places for an unforgettable road trip

Key Functions:

- Responsible for creating all interfaces of new pages, features or redesign on the of Indie Campers' website, considering mobile-first and not mobile-only
- Design and develop the interactions, micro animations and assets on the website
- Working closely with Product
 Managers and other stakeholders
 on the discover step of a new features / functionality / redesign

 Responsible for reviewing, refactoring and components on the CSS.

UX DESIGNER / FRONT-END DEVELOPER

ACE English Malta
www.aceenglishmalta.com
St Julian's - Malta
Jun 2018 - Nov 2019

ACE English Malta is a boutique language school offering the best possible setting for Learning English in Malta, in a friendly and welcoming study environment.

UX ENGINEER

In Loco <u>www.inlocomedia.com.br/en</u> Recife - Brazil Jan 2017 - Jan 2018

InLoco is the greatest mobile advertising platform in Brazil. I worked to improve the mobile ads performance, in both visual and functional ways. I worked alongside another UI/UX designer and an android developer.

WEB DESIGN INTERN

In Loco www.inlocomedia.com.br/en Recife - Brazil Mar 2016 - Dec 2016

Key Functions:

- Responsible for all digital and tech side, from new bookings to data visualization
- Redesigned ACE's website using Wordpress and Front-end technologies - <u>See more</u>
- Improved performance and the SEO of all pages to increase the organic search. Also in charge of website maintenance
- Using Google Analytics and other marketing tools to analyze and to act based on in
- Created digital sales pipeline, focused on bring more direct bookings from diverse countries
- Created dashboards to give data visualization to all teams, from academic to sales
- Rethink and created social media plan (Facebook and Instagram)

Key Functions:

- Improved the experience of the existing ad formats, using user-centered design concepts. -See more
- Created new ad formats throughout the entire process: from design to development. - <u>See more</u>
- Created new features and improved the user experience in the ad creation system.

Key Functions:

Redesigned the In Loco's main site
 See more

I was in charge, with another designer and a marketing analyst, for the redesign and development of the In Loco's institutional site. I also worked on the international version, from the concept to development. In addition, I did diverse activities related to marketing and design.

- Created the international version for international expansion of the business
- Improved the performance of all In Loco's pages.
- Improved the SEO of all pages to increase the organic search
- Added Google Analytics and Mixpanel in the pages to analyze and to act based on in
- Created email templates for internal communication

UX DESIGNER / IOS DEVELOPER

Apple Developer Academy academy.cin.ufpe.br Recife - Brazil Apr 2015 - Apr 2016

The Apple Developer Academy is an education and qualification program in the Apple ecosystem. I participated in multidisciplinary teams with the most various types of profiles. I practiced some concepts of user-centered design and design thinking during the projects.

CEO / CMO

CITi (Junior Enterprise) <u>www.citi.org.br</u> Recife - Brazil Jan 2014 - Dec 2014

After one year as UX Designer and Front-end developer I accumulated the CEO and CMO functions.

Key Functions:

- Developed apps using Objective-C and Swift. In addition, I learned the iOS ecosystem.
- Learned about fintechs and brazilian legislation
- Applied User-Centered Design concepts during the challenges, such as user research, personas, storytelling, paper prototyping, etc.
- Created the experience flow of the apps and created their interfaces alongside an UI Designer.

Key Functions:

- Planned and guided, with the C-level, the business plan
- Managed and helped the C-level
- Assisted the co workers productivity and motivation
- Managed and helped the marketing team
- Identified how marketing would impact in business plan
- Created and managed some CITi events, such as CodeCup, the first hackathon of UFPE - <u>See more</u>

UX DESIGNER / FRONT-END DEVELOPER

CITi (Junior Enterprise) <u>www.citi.org.br</u> Recife - Brazil Jan 2013 - Dec 2013

CITi is a junior enterprise at UFPE and does projects as web systems and mobile apps.

Key Functions:

- Developed the front-end side of the projects
- Designed the user flow and experience of the projects

CERTIFICATES & MEMBERSHIPS

- Interaction South America 2017 Speaker
 - UX + Mobile Ads: Learning to Create Experiences in Mobile Ads <u>See</u> certificate
- The Developer's Conference 2017 Speaker
 - UX + Mobile Ads: Learning to Create Experiences in Mobile Ads See certificate
- Hacker Cidadão Winner See certificate
- Adobe Collection Certification <u>See certificate</u>
- Paper prototyping Course <u>See certificate</u>
- UX Experience Design Na Prática e Acessível See certificate

EDUCATION

- Universidade Federal de Pernambuco, Recife, Brazil
 Computer Science, Bachelor degree
- Apple Developer Academy, Recife, Brazil
 iOS developer and Interaction Designer

PERSONAL INTERESTS

- User-centered Methods
- Front-end development
- Interface design
- Big data
- Marketing
- Digital ads
- Technology / Gadgets
- Video games
- Football / Sports
- Music and dance